hi everyone this is daiyou from ecom ops
today i want to share with you a special
case study
on how we help scale
uh a client store to more than two
million dollars
in under 30 days and usually i talk
about branding and
kind of uh optimization like that
however in this case
there was no branding no customization
just
really great marketing from our client
side and also very thoughtful
aggressive supply chain planning to make
sure
that we help this store reach their true
potential
now we're going to do this case study a
little bit differently because
we actually worked with our client
garrett who's an amazing marketer by the
way i'll leave his contact below if you
want to reach him
but we worked with him on two different
stores both one product stores
with some upsells now last year doing q4
we worked on a store and he made over
two hundred thousand dollars
in q4 which is not too bad however
we even knew at the time that if we were
more thoughtful more aggressive with
supply chain planning
that store could have made a lot more
money and most likely you could have
made
seven figures in last q4 and we took
those learnings and we worked together
uh
our client took a little bit more risk
and during uh roughly covet period
that's where we helped him scale to more
than two million dollars it was 2.4
million dollars at the end
over a period of less than 30 days now
you will actually note here that these
uh
numbers a little bit different because
the top is shopify and the bottom
is actually from click funnels now the
fact that he was using a different
platform a different
marketing strategy that's not something
that we're going to talk about here uh
we're really going to talk about the
supply chain planning which really
applies no matter how you market and
what platform that you actually use
so let's start first with the background
of the first door we help them scale
the product with a children's product
this is obviously not the real product
i'm not going to be able to show you
guys the product because of
client privacy children's products
usually do super well during q4
however uh parents are giving gifts so
these kind of products are really
important to kind of get there
on time for christmas he was able to
make roughly around 225
000 in 40 days in top line revenue
and his margins were very very healthy
as well 25
or so now he was looking at really great
numbers really great roads and it was
super scalable
however we just couldn't get there
because of supply chain issues
and we we just looking at the stats
we're pretty certain that this could at
least have doubled rin revenue but i
think pretty likely have made seven
figures if we had to supply chain
tighter garrett
again he's a great marketer however
honestly he reached out to us a little
bit late i mean he reached out to us in
mid-november
seemingly seems like a great time to
sail however i mean you see later
there's a lot of supply chain
uh preparations you need to make before
then so that you can scale effectively
uh now because it was q4 obviously it
was a short
time frame for selling and given that
this is the children's product
everyone wants it by christmas so our
last ship date last year
for christmas was 12 12 20 19.
he basically had roughly a month a
little bit more than a month of actually
scaling that was actually possible
and the factory
had just really bad lead times they were
completely swamped
now this is not going to be so specific
to this product though during q4
a lot of factories are going to be
swamped
and especially winning products
especially products that are relatively
new
you're gonna have a lot of supply chain
and lead time issues
the other thing as well is that we took
a pretty cautious approach to
stocking we didn't put down for huge
inventory numbers and to be fair i mean
this was not
our client's fault i mean garrett uh it
was our first time collaborating
together
it was a new store he was scaling up
that was you know kind of really
hitting some great numbers however it
was still new so
there was not just as much confidence to
say that okay let's get
you know two thousand five thousand ten
thousand units to enable this kind of
scaling
and so although this store
did really really well and most will
probably call it a success
what happened though was that because of
the factory lead times
demand was always exceeding projections
we'll plan for 100 per day
and then just marketing blew up and he
was selling 200 per day
and we planned for 150 or 200 per day
and he started selling 300 per day
and therefore we were constantly playing
catch up
inventory as soon as it arrived it was
immediately
used up and there were pending orders
and there was like another 5
10 day lead time so there were just a
lot of delays in kind of getting
inventory smoothly and then you know
because we kind of took things
cautiously
we took every batch as a separate order
so
stocking was just simply not predictable
we would try to get 500 1 000 units at a
time and
every single time is a little bit
different because there was no
productivity
and what ended up happening is that it
really
limited the true potential of the store
itself marketing just simply had to slow
down i mean
there was just not enough inventory and
we still wanted to kind of keep a good
processing time and good shipping speeds
so because of the situation garrett
couldn't market
nearly as much as he could even though
the numbers look great
now store number two was when we did
something that was
very very differently now store number
two was during covet and our client was
selling a
covert related product now obviously he
wasn't selling toilet paper but i can't
show you guys the product unfortunately
although this was during covid there's a
lot of learnings in general here and
especially for q4 because there's a ton
of similarities to q4
so first factories were swamped high
lead times everywhere
for this kind of product everyone was
trying to buy it the window to sell this
kind of covert related product was going
to be pretty short
now i won't expect a cover to last as
long but everyone thought that okay you
could sell this for maybe a month or
or a couple months however demand for
this kind of product was really
through the roof worldwide everyone
wanted it
and uh because i mean if you were drop
shipping during coven you knew that
there were shipping delays
everywhere no matter what kind of method
that you used
which means that our processing time
needed to be as short
as possible we couldn't afford to wait
many many days for inventory we need to
get that stock and get it sent out as
soon as possible
but we had our learnings from the first
store we did things
very very differently and uh you know we
really crushed it with this one
how so it was uh it was back in march 16
2020 i actually had the exact
chat screenshot here he said that he had
a new store ready
he didn't start selling scenes yet but
everything was ready on the marketing
side and he was gonna start today
and he wanted the supply chain to be a
hundred percent solid
before scaling again kind of a learning
from last year
and he was also willing to pay
and pay a lot for a high volume of stock
up front so he was willing to be a lot
more aggressive
with this because you know he felt good
about this product he felt good about
the demand
and he had some early promising results
as well
i knew garrett had a lot of experience
what we did is that we
reached out to more than 10 factories it
might have been 15 or 20 actually
to start the process although it was
backlogged everywhere
we were able to secure a couple thousand
units
with a five day lead time which was
actually really great
at that time for this particular product
now so
good thing that we started this process
early because if you look at the time
stamp of this screenshot it was march
18th it was two days later when garrett
actually reached out to me to get on a
call
uh something urgent and he said
basically we need a shitload of
inventory so yes let's talk
right now and get the team started sales
were just
exploding and they were exploding at
thousands
thousands of units per day by the way
not dollars thousands of units per day
within just uh two days of scaling up
and it was
only growing from there so garrett
wanted us to plan
for 10 000 units per day of the main
product and also the upsell
and i'll just tell you right now you
know i've been in the supply chain
business for a long time this is not
easy
10 000 units per day like that's
no joke this was definitely not easy but
you know of course
we believed in him uh garrett was
willing to commit
to the stock invest in the stock and he
just told us to just
go out go crazy and just try to secure
as much as possible
and not only that we discussed
that let's actually find some factories
and reserve their capacity so we have
ongoing stock coming in
so there is less uncertainty with
re-orders
and so here is where i got to give shout
out to
our incredible co-founder maria sun
who's head of sourcing and fact
relationships who ended up working her
magic so what happened was that we ended
up reserving an entire
factory's daily production of 10 000
units per day an entire factory i mean
this is a sizable factory
and uh as backups though we
we second sourced uh two other factories
as backup and uh we actually used some
of that backup as well
so at peak we literally had almost 100
factory workers
producing 15 000 units of this product
per day
uh just for us just for our client just
for this
one store a lot of suppliers i say most
suppliers out there
they just kind of order batches from
like alibaba or the chinese version
alibaba
you know they don't even talk to the
fact they don't even call up the factory
so
what we were able to do because we
actually called these factories up
we built these relationships with them
even just over like a two-day period
we told them hey look we're going to pay
you upfront we're going to reserve all
your capacity
and you are going to get volume from us
and you know what
factories like that factories they
have their own capacity uh to think
about they have their own workers to
think about they don't like it
when they don't exactly know when the
order is coming in
even if the demand is very high so when
someone like us
comes to them it's like hey you don't
have to worry about your orders for the
next month
we're just going to reserve your
capacity and we're going to pay you up
front for for it
or at least as things get made that's
what was able to kind of get these
factories on our side to produce
only for us and just really uh
you know ignore or de-prioritize other
client orders
so i mean this is a perfect example of
how you really need to work with a
supplier you need to work with an agent
who doesn't just order
uh online but they need to be working
with factories directly and they need to
have that experience
working with factories scaling up to
this level or even close to this level
to be honest even a thousand per day is
pretty hard
to scale up in terms of sourcing now the
other thing that was very important is
that
stocking is really only half the story
okay so
at this kind of volume we had to expand
our own fulfillment resources
fulfillment does not scale like
marketing you don't just throw ad
dollars and it scales like that no you
require
space you require people you require
processes
we increase our resources our head count
or fulfillment workers
we had a dedicated team just to handle
qc for this one product now if you
imagine like we're getting 10
15 000 units per day uh if you want to
make sure everything goes out smoothly
you got to get the qc smooth and that
needs people that needs time
so we had a dedicated team just to do
this and we actually did end up
rejecting maybe like one percent
of the products back to the factory so
that one percent doesn't end up with the
customer
and obviously caused a lot of refunds in
the back end so that was very very
important
and and we also had a large team of
fulfillment workers to
process orders now you know especially
in china especially in places like
shenzhen
you can hire short-term workers and it
can ramp up very very quickly
now these things are all very very
important by the way
because uh again fulfillment is not
scalable so you know one when learning
you have is that if you
want to scale up really really high you
really got to work with an agent that
knows what they're doing
and especially if you are going to be
scaling at a number that you think
might be more than what they can handle
then you should have a conversation with
that agent and say hey look
can you expand your team uh can you have
more people
working on my product uh now
some agents don't like to do that
because it's math right more people
means more cost for them that they don't
pass on to the clients
and it means less money in their pockets
now
i think this is kind of like the wrong
way to think about things because
that's a service that i think a
fulfillment agent should be providing
to their clients to be able to scale up
their resources to make sure that they
serve their clients well and achieve
what they actually promise and deliver
and if you guys remember during covet
there were just
incredible delays all around e-pack it
was not working at all
this line there was actually a special
coveted line an express cover line that
was just made for
kova related products to get things
smoothly out of customs as soon as
possible otherwise they were getting
stuck
there were still delays but shipping
still was mostly around one to three
weeks
on this special line compared to like
four to eight weeks or even longer if
you're using something else like epacket
obviously this was more expensive but
our client
wanted to make sure that this project
was going to do well and things would
deliver on time
and obviously he had margins to support
this as well we proactively
manage expectations for our client we
told him that hey you should really talk
to your customers
lengthen your delivery dates and his
team was great at doing that i mean
there's also a high demand product so
they really wanted it
but his team was really great at
reaching out to customers managing them
and making sure that they don't get
unhappy because of these
unforeseen covet delays and
here are the results so for the second
store uh garrett used click funnels and
most of you probably know that if you
make a million dollars in a single
funnel you get the coveted double comma
award which
gary got and he was very very happy for
we were very
happy for him as well uh he or she 2.4
million in total sales in 27 days
uh actually i think i said 29 days
before it was actually 27 days he
corrected me
and a less than 5 refund rate
now normally speaking five percent is
pretty high however there
there were a lot of covet delays and
garrett really wanted to make sure his
customers were happy so he was a little
bit more aggressive the refund as well
but five percent under five percent
during that period the worst of kova
delays
was actually really amazing and uh
less than 0.1 percent defect rate out of
the
hundreds of thousands of units we barely
got any after sales requests for this
well we will take a little bit credit
for this is that you know this is why
exactly we invested in hiring a qc team
a quality control team just for this
product
without that this defect rate would
definitely be higher because as i said
we actually were just
rejected roughly one percent of the
product that the factory sent us
back to them and so that they wouldn't
end up
getting to the customer and obviously
making a negative impact on our client
store
as well so this is a number that we're
very proud of and at the end of it uh he
ended up with 30
net margin so he made very very healthy
numbers from this store all right so a
couple of key takeaways from this
uh especially relevant for q4 which is
uh
well it's not coming up actually it's
it's here but the q4 peak season
november is really coming up soon
in this kind of period where demand is
high supply chain is limited
and you have a short selling period so
the first takeaway is
plan your supply chain as soon as
possible if you're selling in q4 do not
come to us
like on 11 25 that's just not gonna work
i mean you'll sell some but you there's
no time to prepare your supply chain
you need time to talk with factories and
get these relationships building
or no matter what you do it's going to
be too late because maybe these
factories already have commitments with
other big clients and you know maybe
there's nothing around
if you actually start too late and be
able to take a monetary risk i mean look
i know that many of you are in drop
shipping because you want as low risk as
possible and that's totally
fine if you're starting out selling
during normal periods if you want to do
50 orders per day and just make a kind
of decent income stream but if you
really
want to go big if you really want to
take advantage of certain sales periods
you need to take some risk you need to
take some
inventory risk i mean there's no way
around it
second is that you really want to work
with the agent who has
the experience and ability to scale your
supply chain
for you i'll be honest this is going to
be tough
i mean i don't want to just make this a
plug for ecom ops this is something that
we're very good at and we built a lot of
resources
to do this now i mean here's the reason
why like a lot of agents out there
they're not good at this is because they
just don't have that experience or the
resources so
if you want to hit that level uh you
really want to work with us where you
really want to work with an agent
that you really trust is going to do all
these things for you that i just
mentioned
in this presentation my third point is
that i really want to emphasize
working with a good agent is not just to
help you save money not to like improve
your margins increase your customer
experience i mean all of that is
definitely
true however i find that the biggest
value that a really great agent is going
to provide
for you especially for a winning product
you want to scale is that
we're going to provide you with
confidence we're going to provide you
with the confidence to
for you to tell us hey i want to scale
up can you do it for me
now what we're going to do though is
that we're going to tell you we need to
talk to factories we need to plan this
out we can't promise you give us a few
days
and we're going to be able to come back
and you say no problem you know there
might be certain costs involved
there might be time involved and you
might have to continue to adjust
what your order volume might be what
your factory capacity
might be however you're going to be able
to have the confidence
to not only want to make seven or eight
figures
in a couple months but the ability to do
so to
to be able to market well and for the
supply chain to be able to keep up
with your orders or if they can't keep
up at least the agent is going to tell
you so that you don't
oversell and that you don't end up with
huge losses from a lot of refunds and
chargebacks especially
if a lot of your orders don't make it by
christmas don't get me wrong i'm not
saying that if you work with a great
agent you're all of a sudden going to
start making seven figures that is
definitely not true
you have to be great at marketing credit
was all too garrett
credit is all to our clients we can't
market for them we can't give much
marketing advice there's plenty
of resources out there however
we see it over and over again it can be
done a lot of people are saying kind of
drop shipping this kind of model is dead
i mean
it's definitely not dead you have to
know
what you're doing you have to have
confidence in your marketing so
this case study at this level is
probably not relevant for
everyone out there however if you really
know how to scale and you really want to
go big
and you simply just want the confidence
to kind of be able to scale this is
something much
larger than what you might have even
expected
then definitely work with an agent like
us feel free to reach out with someone
like us
now as i mentioned a couple times the
credit for
for this one is really all on garrett
he's
really one of the most impressive
marketers uh we we we've ever worked
with
and we we will continue to work with him
this q4 as well
for some other big projects too garrett
is
a great example of someone who has a lot
of experience who knows what he's doing
and he can consistently
scale up big numbers without his
marketing ability
uh the supply chain is useless i'll put
down his description
in the youtube description and there's
also a link as well he also does some
consulting
for e-commerce businesses so i'll link
his website
if you do want to reach out to him i'm
not getting compensated at all for this
i just want to
show you guys that this is a really good
example of a really great marker he's no
he's actually walking the walk
we've seen him walk the walk
so definitely someone to reach out to if
you want advice
on kind of scaling to this level as well
all right everyone
so hope that was helpful now obviously
gary kind of scaled to a huge level
however i think that you know even if
you're trying to hit
like 500 units a thousand units per day
that's still a lot of units you know so
that's still something that
this is going to apply to you a lot so
if you want
to work with an agent that can help you
scale like this please
reach out to us we are going to start
limiting our client intake in
sometime in november so if you want to
reach out definitely reach out as soon
as possible
because coming in november we're really
going to have to focus on our existing
clients we're going to be super
selective in the kind of clients that we
take in
in november all right guys well hope
that was helpful
again this is daiyou from ecommops see
you guys next time